### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/bryaneppihimer-0650901 (LinkedIn) bryaneppihimer.artstation.com/ (Portfolio)

# Top Skills

Texturing
Modeling
3D

# Bryan Eppihimer

**Principal Character Artist** 

Austin, Texas Metropolitan Area

# Summary

I grew up in Houston, Texas where I developed an interest in the arts at an early age. After high school I went on to major in drawing/sculpting at the Atlanta College of Art before transitioning into computer arts. I have since worked on many exciting projects and continue to hone my craft.

bryan.eppihimer@gmail.com https://bryaneppihimer.artstation.com/

Skills/Software:

Autodesk Maya XSI and MAX

Pixologic zBrush

Adobe Photoshop

Substance Painter

Marvelous Designer

Unreal 4

Cryengine 3

Contributed Work:

Remnant: from the ashes

Breach

Hand of the Gods: Smite Tactics

Smite

The Culling

Heroes of Newerth

Lichdom: Battlemage

Virtue World of Kaneva

Realtime Gaming casino suite

Wizards and Warriors

Nox

Experience

## Meta

Principal Character Artist

December 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Austin, Texas, United States

#### **Twisted Pixel Games**

**Character Artist** 

January 2021 - December 2021 (1 year)

Austin, Texas, United States

(acquired by Meta in 2021)

#### **Gunfire Games**

Senior Character Artist

February 2018 - January 2021 (3 years)

#### Freelance

**Character Artist** 

April 2015 - February 2018 (2 years 11 months)

 Sculpt high detail characters, polygonal models, create LODs and texture the assets based on concepts provided by clients

#### Clients:

Frostburn Studios

GameLoft - NOLA

Garena - CN

Hangar B Productions

Hi-Rez Studios

**Reset Studios** 

QC Games

Xaviant

#### Xaviant

Senior Character Artist

November 2008 - April 2015 (6 years 6 months)

- Create high detail sculpted characters, polygonal models, textures and materials that work within the game budgets
- Collaborate with other departments to develop solid solutions for asset pipelines
- · Create documentation for best practices, pipelines and workflows
- · Create and maintain character artist's schedules

- Review character artwork at various stages to maintain the Art Director's visual style and quality
- · Create character concepts
- Mentor and train other character artists
- Successful shipment of Lichdom: Battlemage

#### Kaneva Inc.

#### **Art Directror**

February 2007 - November 2008 (1 year 10 months)

- · Responsible for managing in-house artists and outsourcing
- · Responsible for negotiating all out-sourced artwork
- Establish art guidelines that improve overall design, quality and consistency
- Establish department schedules and communicate with management to set realistic goals
- Lead team through all aspects of game creation including level design, animation, modeling, texturing, and documentation

## Realtime Gaming

#### **Art Director**

June 1999 - January 2007 (7 years 8 months)

- Responsible for interviewing, hiring, and overseeing artists
- · Establish guidelines for outsource art development
- Maintain quality and consistency of the art department
- Establish all art production deadlines; communicate with developers and management to set realistic goals
- Streamline processes to maximize time and efforts of department while improving overall design
- Lead team through all aspects of game creation including rendering, animation, modeling, texturing, and documentation
- · Oversee all art localization efforts
- · Contribute to successful shipment of over 35 games

#### Heuristic Park Inc.

#### 3d Artist/Animator

June 1996 - June 1999 (3 years 1 month)

- Animate hero and creature characters (recognized with positive feedback at Virgin Interactive and Westwood Studios)
- Hand paint tiling terrain textures, props and character skin variations
- Meet all deadlines for production
- Successful shipment of games (Wizards & Warriors, Nox)

Freelance artist
Freelance artist
1996 - 1998 (2 years)

Darkened Sky Studios

Sand Lyon Studios

Moreland Altobelli Associates, Inc.

Genetic Anomaly

# Education

Atlanta College of Art and Design Computer Arts and Drawing · (1992 - 1996)